15+ Yrs Exp.

B.E (Comps), Mum.

Temp Current Mobile: +249910066331

CV Update: 30-Jun-2020

Add: A-101, Shanti Shreyas, plot-21, Sec-17, Vashi, Navi Mumbai 400705.

Tel: 91-22-2789-7564.

maaluv 81@yahoo.co.in/maaluv81@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Mail:

- Motivator, Team builder, Billing System Expert, Team leader. Subjective experience in telecom billing systems and migrations from legacy systems to new systems.
- Python programmer:- Reconcile HLRs, auditing scripts, replace system Invoice PDFs.
- Rollback of Billcycle due to wrong charges. *

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Configuration			
Tools	Experience	Notes	
PX	6 yrs	Rateplan, Freeunits,SS Services, BS FnF, CCH,PBS	
MI	4 yrs	Discounts, Bonus	
RD	3 yrs	Resources Management	
SY/IR	3 yrs	User	

Mediation		
Comptel	1.5 yr	
Have been Tester for mediation Products ar Complete knowledge Switch files file formats capabilities Meditiation	of and and of	

CX –Front End Customer Care			
Tools	Experience	Notes	
СХ	2 yrs	Defect Analysing Training CRs testing	
CMS	2 yrs	Defect Analysing Training CRs testing	
BillSRV	2 yrs	Defect Analysing Training CRs testing	
SOI tool	Beginner	Batch Processing	

Payments		
Tools	Experience	Notes
CX	2 yrs	Revenue Loss anaylisis
DB	2 yrs	Customer Payments issue
Billing	2 yrs	Defect Analysing CRs testing
PIH/PTH	2 yrs	Batch Processes DefectAnalysis

	Rating	
Tools	Experience	Notes
Rejects Analysis	6 yrs	Defect Analysing Training CRs testing
Dih/Fih/prih Rih/pcch/cch rlh	6 yrs	Defect Analyzing Training CRs testing
Tapin/Tapouts	6 yrs	Defect Analyzing Training

	Provision	ing
Tools	Experience	Notes
Comptel	1.5 yr	Testing with VMD
EMA- GMD	6 ys	Rdrs and EDIFACTS understanding. Configuration

Billing		
Tools	Exp	Notes
ВСН	6 yrs	Defect Analysing Training CRs testing
МІН	6yrs	Defect Analysing Training CRs testing
BillSRV	2 yrs	Defect Analysing Training CRs testing
BGH/Streamserver	4 yrs	Defect Analysing CRs testing

	Fraud	
Tools	Experience	Notes
CX	Beginner	
Business Rules Implementation	Beginner	

Database/ Unix		
Tools	Experience Notes	
Oracle 10 g	6yrs	
BSCS - Related	4 yrs	Baseline Tables n Knowledge
PL/SQL	Intermediate	
Unix scripts	Intermediate	

- 14+ years experience in IT, Telecom domain and billing process.
- Have 10+ years experience of working in Customer- Vendor Environment.
- Thorough knowledge of Telecom BSS Processes. Experience of configuring customized solutions for Telecom Billing Systems BSCS of LHS SEMA Ericsson.
- Completed 2 migration project from PROTEK billing system to BSCSiX R2, and from Tabs to CBiO 2.1 (BSCS IX R3)
- Experience range in Billing System Migration, BSCS TESTING, Implementations, Operator Bussiness Solutions and configuration of 3G services.

15+ Yrs Exp.

B.E (Comps), Mum.

Temp Current Mobile: +249910066331

CV Update: 30-Jun-2020

Add: A-101, Shanti Shreyas, plot-21, Sec-17, Vashi, Navi Mumbai 400705.

Tel: 91-22-2789-7564.

maaluv 81@yahoo.co.in/maaluv81@gmail.com

WORK HISTORY

Mail:

Duration	Organization	Designati- -on	Projects
01-Sep-2019 -till date	Zain Telecom (South	Billing specialist	Replaced BGH for important subscribers, HLR
	Sudan)		reconcile, configurations, reports, CMS log Auditing.
1st Jan 2017- 31-Aug-2019	Huawei Technologies	Billing operations	Zain Managed Services. Tester for CBiO 2.1 to CBiO
		consultant	3.1 Migrator, Trainer
May'2015 – 31st Dec 2016	Consultant for Ericsson	Billing Consultant	System Integrator, Production Support.
	Sudan Cbio Project		
Jun 2014- May-2015	Atos India	Team Leader	Du project telecom, Managed Services.
Apr2010- Mar'2014	Consultant for Ericsson	Billing Consultant	System Integrator, Production Support.
	Sudan Cbio Project		
Jul 2008 – Mar2010	Shilphin India Pvt. Ltd	Solution	Migration from protek billing system to BSCS iX R2 for
		Specialist/Integrator	SABAFON, Yemen mobile operator. Currently Support
			coordinator.
Sep-07' -Jul 08'	Atos Origin India Pvt. Ltd.	System Analyst	New Circle Implementation.
			Client training for BSCS Modules.
Feb 07' - Sep-07'	Tech Mahindra	Technical Associate	Module integration For Tunisia telecom
			Support on BSCS iX R1 for Etisalat Egypt.
Feb 05' - Feb 07'	Hutchison Essar Limited	System Analyst	Testing of new shipments and submitting reports on it.
			Creation or Revision of Rate Plans, Rating Intervals,
			Usage Pkg, Zone Pkg, Time Pkg of 3G services.
			Troubleshooting the Rejected Calls during the Rating
			Procedure.
July 04' –Jan 05'	Cat Education	Teaching Staff	

WORK EXPERIENCE-Key Roles and Areas with Reputed Clients

Zain,

South Sudan:

Billing, Configuration, reports, Trainer, Support

Role: Billing Specialist

Achievements:

- Prepared program to create INVOICE PDF with new and better format than BGH for special customers. (NO BGH development)
- Scripts to reconcile Primary and secondary HLRs with BSCS and SDP (CS).
- CX users audit. Created a program to load CX users actions to a table for audit purpose and to increase security.
- Data fixing and Configurations in BSCS.
- Market products Validation, cleansing and export

Huawei,

North Sudan:

Project: 1) Tester, trainer for migration of CBiO 2.1 to CBiO 3.1

Role: Operation Support

Responsibilities:

Client: Zain

Client: Zain

15+ Yrs Exp.

B.E (Comps), Mum.

Temp Current Mobile: +249910066331

CV Update: 30-Jun-2020

Add: A-101, Shanti Shreyas, plot-21, Sec-17, Vashi, Navi Mumbai 400705.

91-22-2789-7564. Tel:

maaluv 81@yahoo.co.in/maaluv81@gmail.com

- Data Analyzing and Data gathering
- Billing operations
- L1 Integrator and Analyzer
- Data fixing
- Migration Validation, cleansing and export

Ericsson,

North Sudan:

Project: 1) Migration From Tabs to CBiO

Client: Zain Role: System Integrator, Operation Support

Mail:

Responsibilities:

- Data Analyzing and Data gathering
- Design and Migration Solution Documents Preparation
- Migration Strategy and Structure
- Migration Mapping.
- Migration Validation, cleansing and export

Dubai:

1) Task Force Team Project:

> 2) Data Reconcillation Client: Du

Role: Consultant for Production Support

Cairo, Egypt:

Project: 1) Tester & Production Support for in House BSCS Product. Client: Vodafone, Egypt

Responsibilities:

- Give Solutions/ Observation on client raised CSRs.
- Testing of new shipments for the client.
- Installation of shipments and cordination with client for the same.
- CSRs updates and tracking and manging it to been same page with client.
- TTM Tool Testing, It is tool being made as a inhouse project to get the functionalities of MP/MI but using XML. Thus in future Bulk Work/requirement can be faster and efficently error free.

Shilphin, Pune, India.

Project: Migration Client: Sabafon, Yemen. Jul 2008 - April 2010

Role: Solution Specialist Support Co-ordinator

Responsibilities:

- Tested BSCS iX modules before migration.
- Implementation of Cut-over activities.
- Checking Post cut-over activities.
- One point coordinator for Offsite and client needs.
- Testing of COMPTEL Provisioning and Meditation modules.
- Analysis and Implementation of Change Requests Pre & Post migration.
- Developer of Fraud (Credit) Control.

Tasks and achievements:

Developer of Fraud(Credit)Control:

Fraud control is a process that bars the contract if the contract open amount (unbilled amount) crosses the defined thresholds and to activate the contracts if payment is done and available credit is more than defined limit.

Role: Sub Designer-Tester-Implementer of the product.

S/W: PI/SQL. (Packages, Triggers, UNIX scripts)

Testing of Provisioning and Meditation modules:

15+ Yrs Exp.

B.E (Comps), Mum.

Temp Current Mobile: +249910066331

CV Update: 30-Jun-2020

Add: A-101, Shanti Shreyas, plot-21, Sec-17, Vashi, Navi Mumbai 400705.

Tel: 91-22-2789-7564.

Mail: maaluv 81@yahoo.co.in/maaluv81@gmail.com

Provisioning is the process of activating or deactivating services of a contract on Switch when the request is generated by the interface. Mediation is the module that handles the files received from switch and sent to billing system, incase BSCS.

Role: Tester

Test Cases: →

Testing for provisioning For Prepaid contracts (with IN Flags), i.e From BSCS to Switch impacts.

Testing for provisioning for POSTPAID Contracts (with HLR and IN flags)

Testing For mediation for Partial calls with charging.

Testing for mediation(COMPTEL) for Prepaid calls, End to end. i.e from mediation to BSCS System.

Factory and UAT Testing of BSCS iX modules before migration.

BSCS iX supports 10 online executables and 2 Web based applications.

Role:

- Designer and maintainer of Worksheet and test cases.
- Tester for the Modules→ MP, MI, Rating, DB, in house Products, Roaming Partners Info.
- Implementation of Cut-over activities.

Role:

- Creation of scripts for cut over like cross checking Data on S&T related Data.
- Validation of Data for S&T related Data.
- Synchronization of resources between to the two systems.
- Checking Post cut-over activities.

Role:

- Validation of Data.
- Verification of Change request implementations.

Atos Origin, Mumbai, India.

Project: New Circle Implementation. Client: IDEA, India.

Role:System Analyst Sep 07' – Jul 08'

Project: New Circle Implementation. Client: Du Telecom, Dubai

Role:Team Leader Jun-14' – May 15'

Responsibilities:

- Implementation of Business and System scenarios.
- Implementation of initial rateplans, Free units and services.
- Training on BSCS 6 modules → MP(S &T, PX), MI, RA.
- Planning for CR, Resource allocation, Reports, CR follow ups and Team Mangement.

Projects and achievements:

• Implementation of Business and System scenarios:

System and Business Scenarios can be described as artificial intelligence for rating the CDR as per business

logic.

Role: Designer-Tester-Implementer of the product.

S/W: BSCS 6.0 (S&T), Oracle scripts, Excel.

Implementation of initial rateplans, Free units and services:

Rateplans and Services are the components based on which the subscriber of an operator are charged.

Role: Analyzer and Implementer.

Training on BSCS 6 modules → MP(S &T, PX), MI, RA.

A detailed training on the modules of BSCS 6 was facilitated to the client for the period of 3 days.

Role:

- Designer and maintainer of power point slides.
- Trainer → MP, MI, Rating, DB, in house Products, Roaming Partners Info.

15+ Yrs Exp.

B.E (Comps), Mum.

Temp Current Mobile: +249910066331

CV Update: 30-Jun-2020

Add: A-101, Shanti Shreyas, plot-21, Sec-17, Vashi, Navi Mumbai 400705.

Tel: 91-22-2789-7564.

maaluv 81@yahoo.co.in/maaluv81@amail.com

Tech Mahindra, Pune, India.

Project: 1. CR implementation Client: Tunisinia Telecom, Tunisa.

Project: 2. Technical Support Client: Etisalat, Egypt.

Role: Technical Associate Feb 2007 – Sep 07'

Mail:

Responsibilities:

• Support on convergent system BSCS iX R1 for Etisalat operator.

• Implementation of Free units, Promotions and CUG for Tunisinia operator in BSCS 6.

Projects and achievements:

Support on convergent system BSCS iX R1 for Etisalat operator:

Operational and technical support on the billing system.

S/W: BSCS iX R1, Convergence system.

Role: New Business and System scenarios were implemented for roaming requirements

Rejects were analyzed and recycled to reduce revenue loss.

• Implementation of Free units, Promotions and CUG for Tunisinia operator in BSCS 6:

Free units, Promotions and CUG are the components based on which the subscriber of an operator are

given discounts.

Role: Analyzer and Implementer.

Hutchison Essar Limited, Mumbai, India Role:System Analyst

Feb 05' - Feb 07'

Company Profile: Telecom Operator.

Role: Coordination & Management, Support, Designing Business & System Scenarios On BSCS6.

Environment: PLSQL, HP-UX 11x, VB6.0, Oracle 8.i, Toad7.6

Industry: Telecom Operator

Responsibilities:

- Managed S & T configuration of Metro Circle and application development team.
- Leading the Project of Revenue Reject Control.
- Coordination for Mumbai Circle.
- Testing of new shipments and submitting reports on it.
- Creation or Revision of Rate Plans, Rating Intervals, Usage Pkg, Zone Pkg, Time Pkg.
- Troubleshooting the Rejected Calls during the Rating Procedure.

15+ Yrs Exp.

B.E (Comps), Mum.

Temp Current Mobile: +249910066331

CV Update: 30-Jun-2020

Add: A-101, Shanti Shreyas, plot-21, Sec-17, Vashi, Navi Mumbai 400705.

Tel: 91-22-2789-7564.

maaluv 81@yahoo.co.in/maaluv81@gmail.com

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Exams Passed Board/University Year of Passing Percentage

Mail:

Prince 2 Foundation Project Management Certified in 2016.

B.E	MUMBAI	Dec 2004	61%
H.S.C.	MAHARASHTRA	FEB 98-99	64%
S.S.C	MAHARASHTRA	MAR 96-97	68%

HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Have won personality of the year in College for the year 02-03.
- Have won second Prize in Pick and Speak in College in year 02-03.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 27-Sep-1981
Gender: Male.
Married.

Nationality: Indian.

Hobbies: Music, Poems, collection of Books.

• Passport Number K 5633392

References

Name	Position	Contact Info	extra
Bharat Desai	Consultant, currently in USA	bharatsdesai@gmail.com	
Christian	Ericsson Consultant	christian.wiyoto@gmail.com and christian1903wiyoto@gmail.com	
Rainer Puntke	Consultant	rainer.puntke@puntke.de	